<?xml version ="1.0"?>
<world initialarea="startchamber"  language=".txtFramework" author=".txtFramework Team">
  <area id="startchamber" initialdescription="maze_start" status ="NONE">
    <statedescriptor id="maze_start">
      You awake in a sullen chamber with dim light overhead. You cannot remember how you got here but the stench of death
      fills your nostrils, you begin to dry reach. Get a hold of yourself lawrence you say, there must be an explanation
      things like this don't happen to good people. Especially not the founder of non for profit industries the world's largest
      grossing charity. From starving African babies, to abortion clinics, to drug help and so on. Time to escape, Time to move
      as you grow the courage to explore the chamber, you hear faint screams from a distance.

      You scan the dimly lit room and you eye a collapsed wall to the east that is small enough for you to crawl through.
      To the north is a archway with a nice looking cobblestone path it looks much safer than the east.
      To the west a studded metal door is swung ajar, you can enter through the door but you are weary of the entrance as you can
      hear the roar of a fire in the distance.
    </statedescriptor>
    <areacommand name="west" area="collapsedchamber" status="NONE">
     You crawl through the gap in the collapsed wall and skuttle through a narrow passage, that look's like it has been dug out by a tiny exogorths, 
    </areacommand>
    <areacommand name="north" area="pathroom" status="NONE">
      You walk along the cobblestone path, you feel the eyes of others upon you. You bolt to the next chamber.
    </areacommand>
    <areacommand name="east" area="furnaceroom" status="NONE">
      The smell of coals fills your nostrils and you feel like you are walking into the sun. 
    </areacommand>
    <item id="torch" initialdescription="onpodium" collectable ="true">
      <statedescriptor id="onpodium">
        In the center of the room on top of a shoulder height podium, a torch glows so brightly you imagine that it has been
        glowing for thousands of years.Then you realize that thought is ridiculous. The intricate design on the hold suggest that many hours have been spent crafting this lamp.
        The torch looks like it would fit nicely in your hand
      </statedescriptor>
      <statedescriptor id="onplayer">
        A glowing lamp
      </statedescriptor>
      <statedescriptor id="dropped">
        A glowing lamp lying amougst the rubble
      </statedescriptor>
      <itemcommand name="get" statedescription="onplayer" changecollectable="true" collectabledependent="true" areachange="inventory" status="NONE">
        You grab the torch and the light is warm and comforting
      </itemcommand>
      <itemcommand name="drop" statedescription="dropped" changecollectable="true" collectabledependent="false" areachange="NONE" status="NONE">
        You dropped the torch the floor is now illuminated, nice shoes for a charity man
      </itemcommand>
    </item>
  </area>
  <area id="collapsedchamber" initialdescription="collapsedchamber" status ="NONE">
    <statedescriptor id="collapsedchamber">
      A collapsed chamber

      A exit through a tunnel to the south
    </statedescriptor>
    <areacommand name="west" area="pathroom" status="NONE">
      go west
    </areacommand>
    <areacommand name="south" area="startchamber" status="NONE">
      go south
    </areacommand>
    <areacommand name="east" area="deathroom6" status="NONE">
      go east
    </areacommand>
  </area>
  <area id="pathroom" initialdescription="pathroom" status ="NONE">
    <statedescriptor id="pathroom">
     cobble stone room

     
    </statedescriptor>
    <areacommand name="west" area="collapsedchamber" status="NONE">
      You crawl through the gap in the collapsed wall and skuttle through a narrow passage, that look's like it has been dug out by a tiny exogorths, 
    </areacommand>
    <areacommand name="north" area="pathroom" status="NONE">
      You walk along the cobblestone path, you feel the eyes of others upon you. You bolt to the next chamber.
    </areacommand>
    <areacommand name="east" area="furnaceroom" status="NONE">
      The smell of coals fills your nostrils and you feel like you are walking into the sun. 
    </areacommand>
    </item>
  </area>
</world>
